<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Daren Dmytriiev</title><link>https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/categories/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Daren Dmytriiev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bestiary of very very strange mutants</title><link>https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/bestiary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/bestiary/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/bestiary/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Bestiary of very very strange mutants" />&lt;p>The most ambitious project of the creative association &amp;ldquo;Seals &amp;amp; Faces&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>If I&amp;rsquo;m not mistaken, it was in my second year of study. My apartment had recently flooded, and I moved to a smaller one on the outskirts of Kharkiv. There, in the cramped walls of an unknown room, we made big plans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our DnD group collapsed due to moving and internal conflicts. I had some free time and started driving for other companies for money. The process of gathering a team that was willing to pay and not miss sessions was very stressful. I was looking for other ways to make money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now, before my eyes, [Tome of Undeath] (&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.enworld.org/threads/tome-of-undeath.677007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.enworld.org/threads/tome-of-undeath.677007/&lt;/a>) is coming out (this thread is the only mention of it on the Internet that remains). This book was written by an online friend of mine who was a bit more knowledgeable about TTRPGs and game design in general. It was a book about different kinds of undeads. And just as importantly, her book was a commercial success, which greatly inspired our team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without hesitation, we decided that we wanted a bestiary too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="concept">Concept
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I had a very clear vision of what I wanted. I loved hardcore, suspense and weird stuff. The idea of an island where every animal was mutated and became deadly just came out of our daily conversations. Many years later, I realized that this was a very short-sighted decision, given that I was using the DnD5 system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, I was running a DnD campaign for money for people I didn&amp;rsquo;t know, and at the same time the concept of the island was born. The game was similar to West Marches, where players slowly explored the map, opening hexes and finding new adventures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it was from the adventures and problems of that group that new ideas were born. I was annoyed by the one-dimensional nature of the combat in DnD and started doing what any normal DnD newbie does - I started homebrewing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/island.jpg"
width="1280"
height="905"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/island_hu439010e6733fe3009115b1305c7d7fcc_285163_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/island_hu439010e6733fe3009115b1305c7d7fcc_285163_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Concept of island"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="141"
data-flex-basis="339px"
> &lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/island_full.png"
width="1280"
height="905"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/island_full_huc5ee8997c92f70b3e8de257aaee90485_2204361_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/island_full_huc5ee8997c92f70b3e8de257aaee90485_2204361_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Final island version"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="141"
data-flex-basis="339px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="monsters">Monsters
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="weaknesses">Weaknesses
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Each of the monsters had its own &amp;ldquo;weakness&amp;rdquo;. Using the existing system of statuses and resistances, I wanted to give players an advantage in battle that would depend on the amount of knowledge they had accumulated. So all the enemies turned out to be deadly, but at the same time had some critical flaw that instantly made them less powerful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The easiest example is the Candams. Telepathic dogs (it even sounds funny) that use their powers to work well in a group and are quite dangerous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, thanks to their telepathic sensitivity, they are also an easy target for all charming spells. Thus, after charming one of them, each of them will have to make a saving throw.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/dogs.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/dogs_hubeff3edd1b11b026f10ff45028847781_1331812_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/dogs_hubeff3edd1b11b026f10ff45028847781_1331812_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Candams"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="teamwork">Teamwork
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>I was also interested in creating monsters that could synergize with each other, creating particularly dangerous combinations. Unfortunately, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t come up with a systematic solution for this. Instead, I created several monsters that work well together in pairs and essentially create a new combat unit together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s how we got the Vamerps (vampire boars) and the Bolrem (necromancer mushrooms). The Vamerps were strong, but because of their animalistic anger, they were quite easy to stop. Bolremes, of course, revive the corpse and deprive it of such things as emotions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/shroom.jpg"
width="753"
height="586"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/shroom_hu54e96d86b1ada9de617baf77f08de8ad_77247_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/shroom_hu54e96d86b1ada9de617baf77f08de8ad_77247_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Shrooms Concept"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="128"
data-flex-basis="308px"
> &lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/shroom_full.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/shroom_full_hufe0390a9c439f48a5ec6a0b654f44554_1256336_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/shroom_full_hufe0390a9c439f48a5ec6a0b654f44554_1256336_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="shroom_full"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mutations-and-conceptualization">Mutations and conceptualization
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>What turned out to be really cool was the process of generating ideas. We managed to capture this process by simplifying each creature to the animal+feature string. As you can see, each of the monsters I described above is just such a construction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This conceptualization helped us to iterate ideas and come up with new ones very quickly. After this process, we were left with a ton of ideas, which we decided to put into a separate section called Zombie-Mutants. This is a table of 100 mutations that could be used to create new monsters relatively quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, to be honest, looking at this table now, it seems to me that most of the mutations are completely meaningless. Just like in real life, lol.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/miro.jpg"
width="2748"
height="1121"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/miro_hu46589d7eacc82cfcb3b06fa8a2b06562_421600_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/miro_hu46589d7eacc82cfcb3b06fa8a2b06562_421600_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Moodboard"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="245"
data-flex-basis="588px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="coclusion">Coclusion
&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="what-turned-out-well">What turned out well
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Well, the process was incredibly fun. Yes, there were crunches. Yes, we were running out of time. Yes, Dasha and I had an uni exams coming up and it was very difficult. But it was cool in the process, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book itself, although it has some big problems at its core, is nevertheless a great work and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, I improved my English quite a bit, thanks to our editor, Vlad.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-turned-out-badly-and-what-we-learned">What turned out badly and what we learned
&lt;/h3>&lt;h4 id="general">General
&lt;/h4>&lt;p>It was a commercial failure. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t get our book seen by anyone. And even though after &lt;a class="link" href="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/kromvel/" >Kromvel&lt;/a> we came to the conclusion that we had no fan base, no marketing, and no support from social media, we didn&amp;rsquo;t do enough to advertise and gather feedback.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, at the end of the development, I tried to negotiate with an old friend of mine to join our group as a SMM. And he seemed to agree, but in the end, we were still left in the puddle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we had started collecting feedback and looking for coverage on social media from the very first concepts, this situation might not have happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="graphics">Graphics
&lt;/h4>&lt;p>The illustrations were incredible. But my level of layout was not up to par. At that time, I was very bad at working with references. Even though we had a clear reference in the form of Tome of Undeath, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t realize that aesthetic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/snail_concept.jpg"
width="975"
height="625"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/snail_concept_hu2b54f1e09ed755156309d23cc2d4b28d_121426_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/snail_concept_hu2b54f1e09ed755156309d23cc2d4b28d_121426_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Cochenca Concept"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="156"
data-flex-basis="374px"
> &lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/snail_full.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/snail_full_hubeff3edd1b11b026f10ff45028847781_1386650_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/bestiary/snail_full_hubeff3edd1b11b026f10ff45028847781_1386650_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Our GLORIOUS CREATION"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="gameplay">Gameplay
&lt;/h4>&lt;p>Much later, I realized that the problems I was trying to solve with this Bestiary were much more deeply buried in the very essence of the DnD5 system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The very focus of the game is not designed for West Marches, a complex combat system, or knowledge-based mechanics. They had to be solved not by changing monsters and mechanics, but by choosing other tools. Namely, a different role-playing system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the monsters turned out to be too complicated. And there were not enough playtests. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m telling you here, there were almost none at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="in-short">In short
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say it was as bad as I&amp;rsquo;m describing. Rather, I&amp;rsquo;m sure that at that moment we COULD have done better. The fact that we didn&amp;rsquo;t do it means that we didn&amp;rsquo;t reflect enough and get feedback.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this, in turn, was because WE WERE BURNING, WE WERE ON FIRE, WE HAD A LOT OF F-U-N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I don&amp;rsquo;t regret a bit that it turned out the way it did. Every nerve cell was worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FRY MONSTERS AND DRINK MILK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E.S&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You could download &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/361436/Bestiary-of-Very-Very-Strange-Mutants?term=Bestiary&amp;#43;of&amp;#43;very&amp;#43;very" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Bestiary of very very strange mutatnts here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous - &lt;a class="link" href="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/kromvel/" >about Kromvel&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kromvel</title><link>https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/kromvel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/kromvel/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/kromvel/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Kromvel" />&lt;h2 id="context">Context
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>I remember that night in December. It still resonates deep in my heart. It was a real test for me as a dungeon master. There were 2 new players in the game, and I was leading a oneshot that should have been stretched over 4 sessions. Instead, we played from 3 pm on the first day until 8 am on the second. I have never drunk so many energy drinks and hope to never drink them again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the players were absolutely delighted. Without hesitation, we decided that we should pass this on to our descendants and maybe make some money from it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/frog.png"
width="530"
height="502"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/frog_hubf34538e14e8fd38a84871c85e1ca820_144014_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/frog_hubf34538e14e8fd38a84871c85e1ca820_144014_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="We love frogs very much"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="105"
data-flex-basis="253px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-it-was">How it was
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>It was primarily conceived as a commercial project. That&amp;rsquo;s why we wrote in English and posted it on dmsgild, hoping to make a couple hundred dollars. My English wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad, but also it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough for people to enjoy my writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s why we were brought in by the third permanent member of the group, the editor - Vlad, who lived in London and was practically a native speaker (although he was from Moldova). He is a dear person to me, my mentor and good friend, with whom we used to play Hots and DoTA2. And we dreamed of going to The International together and drinking beer together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together, we put down on paper all the adventures that happened to us that day. And we started a long and tense process of proofreading and polishing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="general">General
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The purpose of the oneshot was to expand Acilo setting. I wanted to show that there is life in countries where the group is unlikely to ever visit. And that those events should have an impact on the main campaign.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We moved to a distant northern city called&amp;hellip; Kromvel. This is the last outpost of humanity in these lands. From there, it&amp;rsquo;s just snow, monsters, and a tier S Noite artifact that had just been spotted on magical radar. The group had to reach the target and teleport away. The only difficulty is that the enemy organization has already started hunting and arrived there before ours. So we had to hurry!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the first time, my players felt not like hobos, but like fully-fledged members of society. I gave them artifacts and gold, and they were members of a very respected group of artifact hunters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/girl.png"
width="352"
height="554"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/girl_hu53569c206ad9cb353f5fa8e35c3cb369_202694_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/girl_hu53569c206ad9cb353f5fa8e35c3cb369_202694_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Poor girl, I don&amp;rsquo;t even remeber why we added it"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="63"
data-flex-basis="152px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="plot">Plot
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The city itself was very hostile. Immediately, the players are being followed, and getting transportation is a separate quest. On the way, they will encounter an ambush with a giant crab, a blizzard, hospitable giants, and a dead tavern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As well as dungeons and a big and grandiose battle on a frozen lake!The scale was definitely not vanshot. But I really liked how the game mechanics started interacting with the narrative at that moment. I had an explanation for absolutely everything. Why was the big crab part of the ambush? Because the bandits bought it from a druid smuggler. Why was the crab covered with a tattoo? Because it is a rare endangered species and in order not to be killed they are covered with a hypnotic tattoo. Why is the corridor covered with traps? Because exorcists passed through here and knew they were being chased. And so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/bandit.png"
width="332"
height="718"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/bandit_hu43dab012280203f61a60917fae69e192_176810_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/kromvel/bandit_hu43dab012280203f61a60917fae69e192_176810_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Bandit, one of the crab owners"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="46"
data-flex-basis="110px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best part was probably the fights. It was the first time I felt that the locations for the battle were interesting, complex, and tense. Then the concept of enemies&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;weaknesses&amp;rdquo; began to emerge, which will form the basis of the future [[Bestiary of very very strange mutants]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We earned almost nothing. But I will remember that experience, that orgasm from the birth of your project, bringing it to the end, until the end of my days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read Kromvel &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/348435/Kromvel-Insanity-and-Courage" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next page - &lt;a class="link" href="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/bestiary/" >Bestiary of very very strange mutatnts&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previos page - &lt;a class="link" href="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/chaos/" >Primodial Chaos&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Primordial chaos</title><link>https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/chaos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/chaos/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/chaos/cover_small.png" alt="Featured image of post Primordial chaos" />&lt;p>I think this is the farthest date that I can mark as the start of my personal creative work in narrative and game design.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="context">Context
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In general, it was a great time. I had just moved from Dnipro to Kharkiv to study at the Kharkiv School of Architecture. It was my first attempt at independent living, the freedom made me crazy and I quickly started looking for adventures and money. Very soon, a small group of like-minded people formed around me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We played DnD together. Our adventures were full of all kinds of fun, violence, and friendship. I was the GM and I saw our games as scenarios that I had to invent. The idea of becoming a game designer was just forming in my head. It was a great time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contests">Contests
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Suddenly, I found out that I had Talents in my group. Or rather, our barbarian was a very talented artist. I came across a post from a group called &amp;ldquo;Vsrati DnDshniki&amp;rdquo; (back then in VK). They were announcing a contest for the best dungeon concept. And their prize, oh my God, was a whole paper set for creating dungeons in real life. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suddenly, I find out that I have talents in my group. Our barbarian was a very talented artist. I came across a post from a group called &amp;ldquo;Fuckin&amp;rsquo; DnDplayers&amp;rdquo; (untranslatable). They were announcing a contest for the best dungeon concept. And their prize, oh my God, was a whole paper set of dungeon tiles. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s when our creative group, Seals &amp;amp; Faces came into being. I remember calling Dasha on a summer day in 2020 and shouting into the phone: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;VE COME UP WITH A NAME! We&amp;rsquo;re going to be sealing (? another untranslatable shit. Believe me it makes sense in ukrainian)&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, I had problems with naming even then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we took part in contests for creating artifacts, for new homebrews, and I think for something else. These were quite niche contests and we easily took the top 1. However, we never received the prizes, because of the postal problems between Russia and Ukraine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m adding pictures of what we made below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="artifacts">Artifacts
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/rapier.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/rapier_hu0770dce10deaa38afdc67ef959d7d188_1713532_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/rapier_hu0770dce10deaa38afdc67ef959d7d188_1713532_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Rapier"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
> &lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/sock.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/sock_hu0770dce10deaa38afdc67ef959d7d188_1289674_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/sock_hu0770dce10deaa38afdc67ef959d7d188_1289674_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Halfling Socks"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="and-whole-dungeon">And whole dungeon
&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_01.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_01_huf5a1b88b696bd4bba631c98a71ecfb9b_1019989_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_01_huf5a1b88b696bd4bba631c98a71ecfb9b_1019989_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image 1"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
> &lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_01.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_01_huf5a1b88b696bd4bba631c98a71ecfb9b_1019989_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_01_huf5a1b88b696bd4bba631c98a71ecfb9b_1019989_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image 2"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
> &lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_03.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_03_hu147b27636fddd220a8eca130e4b0afc6_900933_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_03_hu147b27636fddd220a8eca130e4b0afc6_900933_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image 3"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
> &lt;img src="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_04.jpg"
width="1241"
height="1754"
srcset="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_04_hub7e9f90ba8a92435f787eb5653f1edd6_765770_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/p/chaos/dung_04_hub7e9f90ba8a92435f787eb5653f1edd6_765770_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image 4"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="70"
data-flex-basis="169px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acilo">Acilo
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>At some point I decided that our tandem for Seals and Faces was not enough. I wanted &lt;em>&lt;strong>collective creativity&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>. And I called on our DnD group to start by creating a universe in which we would play. Everyone was quite enthusiastic about the idea. I was in charge of text and layout, Dashka (our barbarian - genasi) was responsible for illustrations, and everyone else was generating ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each of us was given a task to write a text about one of the countries of our imaginary universe - Acilo. I tried to divide the work so that we could mix different writing styles, make ideas more interesting, etc. However, it turned out that I had to write most of it anyway&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main goal of this book was to introduce new players to our setting. We had a lot of general ideas, as well as events that we had already played. It was quite difficult to explain everything in words to an outsider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think I thought much about the global concept at the time, but if I were to single out something, it would be &lt;em>Gods&lt;/em>. Every race, every country had a different attitude to the concept of a divine power. Some hated it, some used it, some created it. The only thing that united them was the absence of doubt that the gods were real.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our setting also had a special feature. Back then, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t restrain myself in my game design impulses and wanted to transfer the mechanics of creating wands from Noita to paper. At that time, this game impressed me a lot. I spent a whole campaign on the creation of artifacts, their origins, and all that. In the end, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really come up with a good mechanic, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of fun to think about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read &amp;ldquo;Pain and Suffering in Acilo&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class="link" href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qVA00qspJ3dSjpEvCebWW_C5yBsXPN02/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>here&lt;/a>. (Warning: Russian text)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next - &lt;a class="link" href="https://sobakacece.github.io/portfolio/p/kromvel/" >about Kromvel&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>